

# Apparel Design

Technical Sketching

Tech Packs

Draping

Pattern Making

Transformational Reconstruction

Sewing

Sonabonding

### 3D Digital Prototyping

Clo3D

Optitex

Browzwear

TucaCAD

Lectra

### Computer Aided Design

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign

AutoCAD

#### **Textile**

Weaving

Macrame

# Programming

Python, C++

HTML/CSS, Java Script

PHP, ASP.Net

VB.Net, MySQL

A graduate student inspired by how technical design puts the human experience and functionality of clothing at the forefront of design. By making a conscious choice for all my internships, I have always endeavored in gaining a holistic knowledge of the fashion industry. Aiming to leverage my knowledge and experience of apparel design and digital prototyping to contribute to the field of design.

Address: Ithaca, New York Phone: +16072622166 E-mail: ag2593@cornell.edu

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/aditi99 Website: https://aditi-galada.github.io/portfolio/

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Arts in Apparel Design

December 2022 (Expected)

Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

Cumulative Grade Point Average: 4.2/4.33

Areas of interest: Digital prototyping, human-computer interaction

Professional Membership: Executive Board Member at Cornell India Association

### Bachelor of Fashion Technology

July 2020

National Institute of Fashion Technology, India Cumulative Grade Point Average: 9.8/10.0

Awards: Received Best Academic Performance (2020), Best Graduation Project (2020), Most Commercially Viable Project (2020)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Biba Apparels Private Limited

June 2020 - January 2021

Retail Manager

- Managed a team of 5 retail associates, interfaced with customers, tracked and analyzed customer feedback, managed inventory, forecasted sales, selected product assortment in tradeshows and contributed to the overall success of the store
- Applied retail KPI knowledge to make strategic commercial decisions

#### Kontoor Brands Inc

January 2020 - March 2020

Merchandising Intern

- · Evaluated fit of men's jeans and set fit standard by creating a revised size chart using K-Means clustering algorithm
- · Developed a real-time competitor analysis tool to compare latest product offerings and perform market mapping
- Assisted in design and development of AW'20 product range by creating technical sketches, tech packs and bill of materials
- · Collaborated with costing department to simplify garment construction while maintaining quality standards in order to reduce labor cost.
- Contributed to fit analysis and review sessions with upper management, merchant and design teams.
- Worked on establishing time and action calendar with design and production teams.

# Raymond Apparel Limited

June 2019 - August 2019

Industrial Engineering Inter

- Developed a real time production monitoring system through artificial intelligence
- Increased the productivity of cutting department by more than 50% through industrial engineering techniques and improving ergonomic design of the workplace

Arvind Limited June 2018

Operations Intern

· Comprehended the concept of spun yarn production, woven and knit grey fabric production, dyeing, printing, finishing and textile testing

### **Indian Terrain Fashions Limited**

**July 2017** 

Supply Chain Intern

- · Contributed to the supply chain department in preparing for the AW'18 roadshow by following supplier deliveries, preparing tech packs, and assessing quality of samples
- Implemented preventive maintenance techniques and lean tools such as 5S, Kanban, Jidoka, quick change over

# **CONFERENCE PRESENTATION**

Baytar, F., Kim, Y., Maher, M., Galada, A., and Devine, C. (2021). Examining Crotch Lengths at the Trochanterion Plane by Using 3D Body Scanning to Suggest Considerations for Improving Sizing of Absorbent Underwear Panels and Pads. Poster session presented at the annual meeting of the International Textile and Apparel Association, Virtual. (Forthcoming)

### GRANT

# Human Ecology Alumni Association, Alan D. Mathios Research and Service Grant

Apparel technical designers learn implicitly by conducting iterative problem solving until the desired garment fit is achieved. The ideal solution to support motor learning with 3D simulation would be using an immersive VR environment. Proposed a project to analyze the potential of using Virtual Reality as a training medium for digital prototyping software programs.







#### Relevant Coursework

Understanding Functional Aspects of Clothing and Design

Human Factors: Anthropometrics and Apparel

New Technologies in Fashion Design

Apparel CAD and Grading

Pattern Making

Garment Construction

Undertstanding Body and Pattern Shapes through Draping

Apparel Standards Specifications & Quality Control

Fashion Merchandising



# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

### Prediction Model for Crotch Length

February 2021 – May 2021 · Developed ordinary least square, lasso and principal component regression models using ethnicity, age group and 18 body measurements from the SizeUSA database to predict the crotch length

• Chose lasso regression model as it explained maximum variation in crotch length, 90.53% on the test set, with just five predictors including, height, hips, waist height, knee height and arm length.

• Proposed an equation to improve fit of customized bifurcated garments

### Sakura (Japenese Cherry Blossoms)

# February 2021 - May 2021

• Created an ensemble consisting of a dress and a jacket inspired by Japanese Cherry Blossoms

- Utilized 2D/3D software programs (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Optitex PDS and Clo3D) to visualize and improvise the design
- · Experimented with novel production methods (3D printing, laser cutting & engraving and sonabond ultrasonic fusing)

# Analysis of Customer Behavior in Exclusive Brand Outlets August 2019 – December 2019

- · Investigated the factors affecting customer behavior while purchasing garments in an apparel retail store. Factors identified included product, pricing & promotion, visual merchandising, preferences, and sales assistance
- Verified the results through analysis of sales data of seven retail stores

#### Business Plan for a Smart Apparel Retail Store

#### August 2018 – December 2018

- · Developed a business plan for a retail store loaded with latest technology emphasizing on automation, convenience, and personalization
- Performed market analysis and location analysis and developed strategy & implementation, management summary and financial plan

### Sustainable Apparel Collection

#### January 2018 – March 2018

- · Created a collection of 8 garments ranging from exquisite dresses to daily wear pants and tops, loaded with design elements like pleats and flounces for an intercollege fashion show
- Extracted natural dye and used organic cotton fabric to promote sustainability

#### Web Development

### August 2017 – December 2017

Designed an e-commerce website and created a prototype for a footwear company

· Applied HTML, CSS and Java Script for front end and ASPNET to enable backend activity such as customer registration, cart management and so on

#### Analysis of Handloom Cluster

#### January 2017 - May 2017

June 2021 - August 2021

· Lead a research team on the study and analysis of macro- and micro-environment of a handloom weavers cluster in Thirumalpur producing Kancheepuram saree which is recognized as a geographic indication. The report was submitted to the Textile Ministry of India.

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Cornell Digital Fashion and Body Scan Research Lab

Project Supervisor: Dr. Fatma Baytar

• Collaborated with a five-member research group that analyzed the impact of using of 3D body scanning for fit satisfaction, attitude and purchase intention in online mass customization

- · Conducted literature review, coded experimental data, created pattern markers, and developed customized garments.
- · Compared the fit of garments created using measurements obtained from mobile 3D body scanner and measurements recorded manually by participants

### Hybrid Body Lab, Cornell University

### June 2021 – August 2021

Project Supervisor: Dr. Cindy Hsin-Liu Kao

- · Wove prototypes of plain weave on-skin patches by incorporating circuit in a serpentine pattern using supplemental weave technique to delocalize strain on interconnection joints
- · Brainstormed ideas, created and tested prototypes of detachable and customizable woven patches embedded with Shape Memory Alloy actuators that enabled movements including bending, expanding, and shrinking on actuation. The movements were intensified by utilizing unique properties of yarns and weave structures to vary the stiffness of various parts of the patch.

### **Engaged Cornell**

#### March 2021 - May 2021

Project Supervisor: Dr. Fatma Baytar

- · Created informational material for Course of Trade, a non-profit 120-hour training program that equips the students with garment manufacturing skills
- · Developed instructional training videos on threading various industrial sewing machines, constructing seams, creating shaping elements, and manufacturing garments and bags

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Huang, K., Molla, M. T. I.\*, Roberts, K.\*, Ku, P.\*, Galada, A., and Kao, HL. (2021). Delocalizing Strain in Interconnected Joints of On-Skin Interfaces. International Symposium on Wearable Computers. (Forthcoming) \*Equal second authorship

Ku, P., Huang, K., Galada, A., and Kao, HL. (2021). Patch-O: Shape Changing Woven Patches for On Body Actuation. CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems. (Submitted for Initial Review)